<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer Vision | Alessandro Canevaro</title>
    <link>https://alessandro-canevaro.github.io/tag/computer-vision/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://alessandro-canevaro.github.io/tag/computer-vision/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Computer Vision</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://alessandro-canevaro.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Computer Vision</title>
      <link>https://alessandro-canevaro.github.io/tag/computer-vision/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Tracking and Classification</title>
      <link>https://alessandro-canevaro.github.io/project/perception/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alessandro-canevaro.github.io/project/perception/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;activity-goal&#34;&gt;Activity goal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The objective of the final project is to detect, track, predict, and classify moving objects, whether
they are occluded or unoccluded. In our scenario, we are given a stereo camera setup looking over
a conveyor belt. Random objects are placed at one end of the conveyor belt at regular intervals.
This simulates a general-purpose case where these objects need to have their attributes recognized
in real-time. The main steps required to achieve our project objectives are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Camera Calibration and Rectification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Object Detection and Tracking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Object Classification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Detection</title>
      <link>https://alessandro-canevaro.github.io/project/boats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alessandro-canevaro.github.io/project/boats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;activity-goal&#34;&gt;Activity goal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim is to develop a computer vision algorithm that can detect boats in an image. Specifically,
it should draw a rectangular bounding box around each founded boat, and it should work correctly
even when the image has no boats in it. Note that boats can appear from any perspective, and they
can be very different: from small dinghies to cruise ships. The intersection over union (IoU) metric
is used on the provided test images to measure the algorithm’s performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;adopted-approach&#34;&gt;Adopted approach&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the great variety of boats and the availability of a large data set of images, a machine learning
approach seems promising. Hence the use of a neural network in the proposed solution. In particular,
the developed algorithm initially extracts features (key points and descriptors) from the image, then
classifies the descriptors as boat/non-boat, and lastly, builds the bounding boxes. The last step is,
in turn, composed of several sub-steps. The algorithm first generates a probability density function
(PDF) of the potential locations of the boats. The PDF modes are then clustered using the mean
shift algorithm, and finally, the bounding boxes are generated with a simple iterative procedure. The
complete algorithm is here summarized:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extract features key points and descriptors from the to-be-detected image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classify each descriptor as boat/non-boat using the trained classifier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate the probability map of the possible positions of the boats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find and cluster the modes of the above probability density using the mean shift algorithm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prune and suppress &amp;ldquo;weak&amp;rdquo; clusters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For each cluster, generate the bounding box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
