<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Other | Alessandro Canevaro</title>
    <link>https://alessandro-canevaro.github.io/tag/other/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://alessandro-canevaro.github.io/tag/other/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Other</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://alessandro-canevaro.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Other</title>
      <link>https://alessandro-canevaro.github.io/tag/other/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systems Optimization</title>
      <link>https://alessandro-canevaro.github.io/project/optim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alessandro-canevaro.github.io/project/optim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;activity-goal&#34;&gt;Activity goal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an input you are given:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(1) An application model consisting of a set of TT tasks and a set of ET tasks,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(2) An architecture model consisting of one core that schedules TT tasks with timeline scheduling and ET tasks with polling servers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will have to design and implement an optimization algorithm that determines an optimized solution which consists of the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(1) The number of polling servers, which then become extra TT tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(2) For each polling server (task), the period, budget, and deadline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(3) Which sub-sets of ET tasks are handled within the respective polling servers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(4) A TT schedule such that also the TT tasks are schedulable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution should be optimized such that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(1) Both the TT and ET tasks are schedulable, i.e., they complete before their deadlines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(2) The ET task separation constraints are satisfied.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(3) The average worst-case response times (WCRT) of all tasks (TT and ET) is minimized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disease Tracker</title>
      <link>https://alessandro-canevaro.github.io/project/mbse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alessandro-canevaro.github.io/project/mbse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;activity-goal&#34;&gt;Activity goal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus of this project is to identify if a wearable device can be used to reduce the spreading rate of COVID-19 by tracking a person’s body temperature and oxygen saturation in the blood in order to determine with a certain probability whether or not she might be infected, and if that is the case, warn her as well as the others in close proximity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matematica Dolce</title>
      <link>https://alessandro-canevaro.github.io/project/dolce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alessandro-canevaro.github.io/project/dolce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;activity-goal&#34;&gt;Activity goal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matematica Dolce is a handbook of mathematics for secondary school written by several hands and with an open-source licence.
The collaborative mode allows a strong sharing in the choice and construction of materials and ways of presenting the topics.
Then book is freely downloadable from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.matematicadolce.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.matematicadolce.eu/&lt;/a&gt;, and it is also available as LAMBDA book for blind students at &lt;a href=&#34;https://ddmath.eu/en/matematica-dolce/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://ddmath.eu/en/matematica-dolce/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I collaborated with the project coordinator (prof. D. Zambelli) in writing a program to automatically generate maths exercises.
The code is written in Python and the output is automatically formatted in LaTeX.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
